（春野はるのサクラ）ハア ハア…
あっ はっ…
あれが本体？
That's his real body.
After twenty years,
what say we face each other?
（チヨ）20年ぶりに
まみえようではないか
（テマリ）ん…
What took you so long?
（カンクロウ）遅かったな
（テマリ）ハッ…
これでも飛ばして帰ってきたんだ
But I flew back as quickly
as I could.
More to the point,
それより 国境警備の代役
よこすのが遅すぎだぞ
you took too long to send over
a substitute border guard.
Your planning was bad.
（テマリ）お前の手はずが悪い
これでも 病み上がりに
お前のわがまま聞いてやったんだ
That's no way to show
your appreciation.
I carried out your selfish request
despite recovering from an illness.
その言いぐさは ねえじゃん
（舌打ち）
（テマリ）はあ…
ふん！
さて 行くか
Well... Shall we get going?
Yeah.
ああ
Yes, sir!
（マツリ）はい
あっ
It can still move?!
（サクラ）まだ動くの？
As I thought.
（サソリ）やっぱりな
Just what I'd expect
from my old granny.
さすが 俺のババアなだけはある
どうりで この小娘まで
俺の仕込みをかわせたわけだ
No wonder this little girl was able
to dodge my hidden weapons.
After all, the old lady who can see
past my attacks was controlling
俺の攻撃を見切れるババアが
傀儡くぐつの術のチャクラ糸で
小娘を操ってたんだからな
the little girl with Chakra threads
used for the Puppet Master Jutsu.
He found out.
（サクラ）バレた
What's more, you were so kind as to
attach threads of Chakra to Hiruko's tail.
（サソリ）それにだ
ご丁寧に ヒルコの尾にまで
チャクラ糸を
But to think that I'd notice it
しかし 尾の動きを止められて
初めて気づかされるとはな
after the tail's motion had been
brought to a halt...
（サソリ）最初に
クナイで攻撃したときだろう
It was when you first attacked
with the Kunai Knife, wasn't it?
Threads of Chakra attached
to the Kunai Knife
クナイに付いていたチャクラ糸を
latched onto the tail
when it repelled the Kunai Knife.
クナイをはじいた尾に 付け替えた
I suppressed my Chakra as much
as possible so as not to be seen,
ほう 目に見えぬよう
チャクラを ギリギリまで
抑えていたというのに
and yet you still figured it out.
I'm amazed.
よく分かったな
なっ…
But of course.
（サソリ）そりゃそうだろ
After all, the one who hammered
the principles of puppetry into me was...
傀儡遊びを 俺にたたき込んだのは
ほかでもない…
none other than you.
あんただぜ
Yes.
（チヨ）ああ
But the show ends today.
じゃが 遊びはきょうで終わりじゃ
That is my intention as well.
（サソリ）こっちも そのつもりだ
あっ…
Well then, will things proceed
as simply as that, I wonder...
（サソリ）
さあて そう簡単にいくかな？
Granny Chiyo...?
チヨバア様よ
Granny Chiyo?
チヨバア様
Is he... Is he Sasori?
こいつが…
こいつが サソリ？
What is going on?
どういうことじゃ
He's just as he was before...
He hasn't aged a bit.
（チヨ）
昔のまま 年を取っておらぬ
What's going on?!
（サクラ）どういうこと？
I was told Sasori broke off from
the Hidden Sand 20 years ago...
サソリは 20年も前に
砂隠すながくれを抜けたって
There's no way that
he could be this young.
こんなに若いはずが…
♪～
～♪
Sasori's Real Face
（うずまきナルト）クソ！
Damn!
（はたけカカシ）
さっき 中から聞こえてきた音は
The sound that I heard coming
from inside just a while ago...
すでに 戦闘が
始まっているのは確かだ
There's no doubt that
the battle has already begun.
I'd like to get a grasp
of the situation, but...
状況を把握しておきたいところだが
You! Return Gaara to us!
（ナルト）てめえ！
我愛羅があらを返せってばよ
It's only a matter of time
（デイダラ）サソリの旦那が
中の連中を始末するのも
before my man Sasori does away
with the group inside.
時間の問題だな うん
If my man comes out,
旦那に出てこられると
then the whole point of using this one
to draw out the Jinchuriki will be lost.
こいつを使って 人柱力じんちゅうりきを
誘い出した意味がなくなるな
（ナルト）うっ… 野郎
You jerk!
I won't let you get away.
逃がしゃしねえ！
待ちやがれ！
Hold it right there!
（カカシ）ナルト 待て！
Naruto, wait a minute!
えい カカシ先生は
サクラちゃんのほうを頼むってばよ
Kakashi Sensei,
you go look after Sakura!
（カカシ）ったく…
Good grief.
（無線のスイッチ音）
（カカシ）ガイ
Guy, how are conditions
over there?
そちらの状況は？
（マイト･ガイ）うお！
（ガイ）はあ－！
どっ…
ハア ハア…
すまぬ カカシ
Sorry Kakashi, it looks like things
will still take a while over here.
こっちは まだ少しかかりそうだ
（日向ひゅうがネジ）ハア ハア…
（ネジ）ええい！
回天かいてん！
Rotation.
If detaining someone is your objective,
there's no better way than this.
足止めが目的なら
これ以上はない方法だな
（テンテン）ハア ハア…
If your opponent has exactly
the same abilities as you do...
相手が 自分と全く同じ能力を
持ってるなら…
（ロック･リー）そう簡単に
けりはつきそうもありませんね
It probably won't be that easy
to bring matters to a close.
Splendid move, Mr. Imposter.
お見事です
偽物君
（カカシ）
クソっ 援護は当分 無理か
Damn... Looks like it's impossible to
expect back-up for a while.
サクラ チヨバア様
Sakura, Granny Chiyo,
hold down the fort a bit longer!
もう少し ふんばってくれよ
絶対ぜってえ 逃がさねえ！
There's no way I'm going
to let you get away!
They're coming, aren't they?
（デイダラ）来てるな うん
しっかり ついてこいよ
Better keep up!
そしたら
ちゃんと始末してやるからな うん
And then,
I will settle matters properly...
Stop!
止まれ！
うっ…
What's wrong, Kankuro?
どうした？ カンクロウ
ここで休憩をとる
We'll rest here.
何？ どういうことだ カンクロウ
What?! What do you think
you're doing, Kankuro?!
There's no time to rest easy
in a situation like this!
こんなところで
ちんたら休んでる暇などない
そう焦るなって
Don't be so impatient...
That's not like you, Sis.
いつもの姉貴らしくないじゃん
あっ はっ…
（マツリ）
申し訳ありません テマリさん
I'm sorry, Miss Temari.
（砂すなの里さとの忍）ちょっと…
ちょっと休めば すぐ走れます
Just a little while...
If we rest just a little while,
we'll be able to start
running again right away!
（砂の里の忍）
少し休憩させてください
Please let us rest a little while.
あっ だらしないぞ
You guys have no discipline.
And you call yourselves Shinobi?!
それでも お前ら忍か！
Stop being unreasonable.
（カンクロウ）無理 言うじゃん
こいつらだって
24時間 交代での国境警備
These guys took turns guarding
the border for a whole day.
And no sooner had they returned
to the village,
そのまま里へ とんぼ返りしたうえ
ここまで走ってきたんだ
they had to run all the way here...
However top-notch Shinobi they may be,
どんな優秀な忍だって
これ以上は 無理させられないじゃん
you can't force them to do
more than this.
No, we're okay!
いえ 大丈夫です
We can't be resting while
Lord Gaara is in trouble!
我愛羅様が ピンチのときに
休んでなんかいられません
（砂の里の忍）あっ
風影かぜかげ様のために
俺たちが 今できることを
We should do what we can
for the Kazekage's sake!
Yes, for the Kazekage's sake!
そうだ 風影様のために
Miss Temari! Let's head out.
テマリさん 出発しましょう
You guys! That's the spirit!
お前ら よく言ってくれた
Now, now,
you shouldn't get so fired up about it.
（エビゾウ）
まあ そう熱くなるでない
Ebizo...
（テマリ）エビゾウじい様
（エビゾウ）
忍たるもの いかなるときも
冷静さを失ってはならんのよ
A Shinobi should never lose
his composure under any circumstances.
それを忘れ １人深追いしたのは
今回のカンクロウの失敗
Forgetting that and pursuing
the enemy too far all by himself
was the cause of
Kankuro's recent failure, wasn't it?
違うか？
（カンクロウ）ハッハハ
それに 今のお前たちは
まるで周りが見えておらん
Besides, in your current state,
all of you are not being aware
of your surroundings.
What do you mean by that...?
それは 一体…
まあ あれを見てみろ
Well, look at that.
（テマリ）ん？
（マツリ）あっ あれは
Th-That...?!
（エビゾウ）恐らくは
木こノ葉はと暁あかつきが やり合った跡だろうよ
That must be the remains of the battle
that Akatsuki fought with the Leaf.
（テマリ）あっ それでは…
That means...
（エビゾウ）そうじゃ
Yes. You have to assume that
we have already entered their territory.
わしらは すでにヤツらの
テリトリーの中に入ったと
考えるべきじゃろう
There's no telling what kind of traps
they may have set up ahead.
これより先 どんなトラップが
仕掛けてあるかも分からん
そんな場所へ
足を踏み入れようとしとるときに
When you're about to set foot
in such a place,
you'll be annihilated in no time
if you go dashing in,
今のお主らのように
疲れきった状態で飛び込んでみろ
exhausted the way you all are now.
あっという間に全滅よ
（２人）あっ
あっ
あっ…
ちょうどよい
This is just perfect.
While you're resting, I'll tell you all
a story about the old days.
休憩がてら
わしが 昔話でもしてやろう
あれは ずいぶん昔のことよ
It was long, long ago.
I'm sure you must
have heard of it...
お主らも
耳にしたことぐらいはあるじゃろ
三代目風影の事件は
The incident of the Third Kazekage.
ん あっ 三代目風影
The Third...Kazekage?
ああ 先々代の風影よ
Yes... The one before
the previous Kazekage.
三代目は 歴代風影の中でも
最強とうたわれておった
Of all the Kazekage
down through history,
the Third Kazekage was
said to be the most powerful.
その三代目が 何者かに
さらわれるという事件が起き
Then the incident occurred when
someone kidnapped the Kazekage.
里中が躍起になり
三代目の消息を追った
The entire village got all excited
and went out seeking news
of what had become of
the Third Kazekage...
今にして思えば
Looking back upon it now,
you would have to say
that they simply lost their cool.
冷静さを欠いておったとしか
言いようがない
里の守りは 手薄となり
The village's guard wore thin,
allowing the enemy to intrude,
and panic ensued.
敵の侵入を許し 混乱した
If they had dealt with it
a little more coolly at the time,
あのとき
もう少し冷静に対処しておれば
その後の戦争も
回避できたろうによ
the subsequent war
could have been avoided.
I am painfully aware of how
you all feel right now...
今のお主らの気持ちは
痛いほど よく分かる
But...you mustn't repeat
the same mistakes
じゃが だからといって
三代目のときと同じような過ちを
繰り返してはならぬのよ
that were made back in
the days of the Third Kazekage.
Ebizo...
エビゾウ様
それで その後
三代目の消息はつかめたのですか？
did they ever learn what happened to
the Third Kazekage after that?
After that, the Anbu Black Ops
continued to investigate in secret,
あれから暗部あんぶが
ひそかに調査を続けてはおるが
but no body was ever found,
遺体はおろか 移動した痕跡すら
いまだ出てこんのだ
nor any sign that the Kazekage
had been removed...
What's wrong, Granny Chiyo?
（サソリ）どうした？ チヨバア様
Are you so filled with emotion
that you cannot speak?
感激のあまり声も出ないか？
That's not surprising.
無理もない
20年ぶりの再会だからな
After all, it's our first reunion
in 20 years.
（チヨ）サソリ お主
Sasori, you...
（サソリ）ついでだ
とっておきを見せてやる
While I'm at it,
I'll show you something special.
感激すること請け合いだぜ
It's guaranteed to move you.
A collection that gave me
a hard time when trying to kill it, but...
殺すとき 苦労したコレクションだが
“三”？
Three?
それだけに いちばん気に入っている
That's why I like this best of all.
そ… それは
Th-That... It couldn't be!
まさか！
What? What's wrong?!
何？ どうしたんです？
それは… 三代目風影
That's...the Third Kazekage...
えっ？
What?!
The Third...Kazekage?
三代目風影
フフフ…
How about it?
どうだ？
懐かしいだろ チヨバア
Doesn't that take you back,
Granny Chiyo?
チヨバア様 三代目風影って…
Granny Chiyo, the Third Kazekage...?
How could this have happened?
なんたることじゃ
Then...
それじゃあ
It was over ten years ago
（チヨ）もう10年以上も前じゃ
that the Third Kazekage suddenly
disappeared from the village.
三代目が突然 里から消えたのは
（サクラ）はっ…
We scoured the countryside,
but we were never able to find him.
（チヨ）八方 手を尽くしたのじゃが
とうとう見つからなんだ
最強の風影じゃったが
He was the most powerful
of all the Kazekage's, but...
Sasori, you...?
サソリ お前が…
And so what if I did?
だったら どうした？
Do you mean to say that a retired old lady
with one foot in the grave
隠居した死にかけのババアが
三代目の敵討ちでもするってのか？
is about to avenge
the Third Kazekage?
Tough luck...
ご苦労なこった
Retired, with one foot in the grave.
That may be so,
（チヨ）隠居の死にかけでも
わざわざ重い腰を上げてみるもんじゃ
but it was worth hauling
my heavy behind over here.
I'd have too many regrets
if I were to die now.
まだまだ
死ぬには心残りがありすぎる
わが孫が 悪党に
身を落とすだけならまだしも
It's bad enough that my grandson
got himself mixed up
with a bad crowd...
but to think that you'd betray the village
里を裏切り ３度までも
風影に手をかけようとは
and try to meddle with the Kazekage,
for the third time!
“３度”？
Third time?
It was Orochimaru
who killed Gaara's father,
（チヨ）我愛羅の父 四代目風影を
殺したのは大蛇丸(おろちまる)じゃったが
the Fourth Kazekage, but...
それを手引きしたのは こヤツじゃ
the one who guided them
was Sasori!
そして 今回の我愛羅も
And this time,
Gaara and even the Third Kazekage...
さらには三代目まで
（サソリ）おいおい
四代目つうのは 俺は知らねえぜ
Hey, hey, I don't know anything
about the Fourth Kazekage.
The one who guided them
was my subordinate.
手引きは 俺の部下がやったことだ
In that case, it's the same
as if you did it yourself.
ならば お前がやったのも
同じじゃろうが
関係ないと言うのか
Can you really say that
you were not involved?
Indeed, I was originally paired with
Orochimaru back at the Akatsuki,
（サソリ）確かに 暁では
もともと大蛇丸と組んでたから
いろいろやったが
so I did lots of things but...
あっ…
あなたは…
You...
あなた 大蛇丸と組んでたってことは
If you were paired
with Orochimaru...
then that means you know
about Orochimaru.
大蛇丸のことを
くっ…
In that case, there're a lot
of questions I need you to answer!
なら いろいろと聞きたいことがあるわ
（サソリ）フッ
（チヨ）サクラ…
Sakura...
あいにくだったな
Unfortunately,
I must take you two out
俺は お前らを片づけて
and go capture that Jinchuriki.
さっきの人柱力を
捕まえなきゃならない
I hate to keep people waiting,
人を待たせるのは 嫌いなもんでね
so I have no time
to answer your questions.
質問に答えてる時間はない
さて…
So...
shall we get right to it?
もうやるか
Here it comes!
（サクラ）来る
うっ…
（チヨの掛け声）
（サクラ）ああっ…
死ね！
Die!
（サクラ）うっ
He's fast!
（チヨ）速い！
To think that Hiruko's tail
fell to pieces...
ヒルコの尾が バラバラとは
やるなチヨバア
You've got some
pretty good moves, Granny Chiyo.
In that case, how about this?
なら これでどうだ
ああ… いかん
Oh no!
そらあ！
Take this!
サクラ！
Sakura!
（サソリ）ちっ 仕損じたか
Damn. Did I botch it?
（サクラ）はあ 助かった
Saved!
With the old lady manipulating things,
it's impossible to get anywhere.
（サソリ）ババアが操ってんなら
らちが明かねえ
（サクラ）あっ
In that case.
だったら…
あっ
いかん！ サクラ息を止めろ！
（サクラ）毒…
（サソリ）
毒煙なら 動きは関係ねえぜ
サクラ！
♪～
～♪
大変です ガイ先生
どうした？ リーよ
今 入った情報によると
きょうのミニコーナーの主役は
カカシ先生だそうです
なんだと！
俺たちが戦ってる間に
そんな おいしい企画を
こうなったら さっさと片づけて
僕たちも
参加するしかありませんね
青春フルパワーだ！
間に合うものか
なせば成る なあテンテンよ
あれ？ テンテンは？
ＭＣに抜てきされたって
さっき 張り切って出てった
なんですと！
この裏切り者め！
やっほ～
里の有名人を紹介する このコーナー
今回 紹介するのは
木ノ葉一の業師 はたけカカシ先生
…なんだけど
まだ来てないのよね
女性を待たせるなんて最低
うわっ
（カカシ）どうも
やっと来た もう
（カカシ）やあ すまん すまん
とにかくゲストも来たし
改めて 紹介いってみよう！
ナルト サスケ サクラの
第７班の隊長で
木ノ葉でも トップクラスの実力者
うちは一族以外で
唯一 写輪眼しゃりんがんを持ち
相手の術を
写し取ってしまうことから
付いた呼び名が…
（カカシ）
じゃなくて…
…でしょ
（テンテン）
そんなカカシ先生の
唯一のオリジナルにして
最強の術こそが 奥義千年殺せんねんごろし
（カカシ）違～う 雷切(らいきり)だ 雷切
（カカシ）もう ちょっとテンテン
俺だけ扱いひどくない？
そ～んなこと
ないですよ
アッハハハ…